REX CAMACHO ROBLES

437 988 1181 rxcrobles@gmail.com

33 Porchester Drive Scarborough, ON M1J 2R4

PROFILE

Experienced Lab Assistant with more than 10 years of administrative experience, proficient at supporting teams by performing standard laboratory office functions efficiently, with a strong ability to make appropriate technical decisions critical thinking and problem solving.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Laboratory Assistant - Research Division , Weill Cornell Medicine, Doha, Qatar — March 2017 - December 2022

- Responsible in supporting the technical requirements for implementation of laboratories.
- Data input of information into the laboratory computer information system
- Prepare materials needed in lab research courses and enforce laboratory safety procedures.
- Maintain contact and consults with end users to prepare specifications for items/ equipment or services as required.
- Prepares Lab supplies Store orders and create shopping cart.
- Receive, generate and/or process supplier quotes, purchase orders (POs), distribute to management and/or applicable departments as needed for review, approval, and storage.
- Communicate the status of purchases within the department to ensure products are received in a timely manner.
- Work weekly report of Open POs and Invoices for reconciliation.
- Operate and maintain core facilities (sterilizers, media washers and ultrapure water systems) following equipment and laboratory guidelines and established Standard operating procedures.
- Collect, wash, sterilize and deliver all lab ware and sterilized media as required from all research related areas.
- Disinfect, maintain and clean of laboratory areas, special procedure rooms, core equipment and research office space.
- Assist with receiving, processing and delivery of research shipments and research store orders, maintains stocks and organizes research store.
- Move specialized equipment and supplies, refilling LN2 (Liquid nitrogen), containers, obtaining dry ice, defrosting freezers and help maintains Lab Temperature Monitoring System.
- Supply and removal of biohazard waste disposal material and lab tissue for all labs.

- Collect, sterilize, and dispose of biohazard waste for all labs and notify the lab team about violations they find regarding proper waste disposal.
- Deliver and collects clinical samples.

Lab Technician, Schlumberger Overseas S. A., Doha Qatar — March 2014 -February 2017

- Receive Lab Analysis Request from Field Engineers and perform tests like rheology, thickening time, fluid loss, free fluid, etc.
- Receive and record chemical, cement, & water samples from the rigs & other remote location.
- Perform chemical inventory for the laboratory and disposes redundant chemicals, cement, and water samples.

Maintenance Administrator, Schlumberger Overseas S. A., Doha Qatar — February 2005 - February 2014

- Act as the primary contact and provides support for Maintenance Department.
- Implement and deliver effective maintenance strategies and procedures to quality management standards for all day-to-day maintenance work.
- Coordinate planned and unplanned maintenance outage work, including control of emergent works, permit issues, material issues, resource issues and program updates.
- Receive and encode new and finished Work Order of the equipment from the workshop, vessels, and from the rigs using a computerize maintenance management system software called MAXIMO.
- Generate reports on the received, finished, and pending Repair Order of the equipment.
- Monitor the maintenance cost of each repair of the equipment.
- Monitor the Preventive Maintenance schedule of the equipment.
- Ensure all procedures, documentation and manuals are kept up to date and any additional training is completed in timely manner.
- Keep a complete documentation service and archive digital files for the segment.
- Assign Preventive Maintenance program for each equipment. Assists the store man in monitoring and ordering spare parts for the warehouse.
- Track the transfer of equipment from one location to another. Responsible for the monthly reports for the manager's monthly meeting relating to maintenance.
- Responsible for attending the daily production meeting and overseeing the daily works coordination meeting.
- Monitor the inventory of the spare parts of the equipment. Preserves harmonious and productive relations with the Engineers, Contractors, and Operations.

- Generate monthly report for the received and used spare parts of the maintenance department.
- File maintenance reports and spare part's invoice.
- Direct the weekly review of all outstanding jobs of technicians with their respective Maintenance Supervisor records all their activities and initiates actions accordingly.

IT Technical Clerk, Al-Muftah Group of Companies, Doha Qatar — November 2004 - February 2005

- Provide IT support and ensuring systems are maintained and supported based on the company standards.
- Ensure that all staff's requests are dealt with appropriately and in accordance with defined policies and procedures.
- Set up new user's account and profiles dealing with password issues.
- Perform back up, recovery and systems monitoring.
- Install and configure computer hardware operating systems and applications.
- Perform basic computer repairs and analyses system when malfunction occurs.
- Monitor the stocks of the IT department.
- Coordinate and schedule work with vendor service providers.

EDUCATION

Centennial College, 941 Progress Ave, Scarborough, ON M1G 3T8-

Ontario College Advanced Diploma in Health Informatics Technology , January 2023 - present

AMA Computer College, Makati City, Philippines - Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, April 2004

PERSONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Skills and Knowledge:

- Excellent communication skills written and oral.
- Effective administration skills with the ability to be able to follow procedures with minimal supervision.
- Time Management and Organizational operational skills
- Competent in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Visio 2003, SharePoint
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CSCO11988067)

Competencies and Personal Attributes:

- Ability to work effectively with different types of nationality.
- Fast learner and willing to take on new challenges.
- Assertive, people oriented and self-motivated

CERTIFICATIONS

APTECH Qatar Computer Education Centre, Doha Qatar — CISCO Certified Network Associate, June 2011 CSCO11988067

REFERENCES: Available Upon Request